Guide to the United Methodist Church Records, 1784-1984, bulk 1800-1940
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- N.C. Conference Records Series, 1784-1974, bulk 1838-1939
  - Circuit, Charge, and Church Records Subseries, 1784-1974, bulk 1841-1919
    - Caswell Co., 1844-1877, 1883-1930
      - Leasburg Circuit, multiple districts, 1883-1930
        - [Leasburg Church, 1883-1902: Found in Caswell Co., Leasburg Circuit, Bethany Church, Church Conference Minutes, 1884-1902.]
        - Quarterly Conference Minutes
          - 1883-1886(M-2878)
          - 1887-1890(M-2790) (Box NCC34)
          - 1891-1894(M-2791)
          - 1895-1898(M-2792)
          - 1899-1902(M-2793)
          - 1903-1906(M-2794)
          - 1907-1910(M-2795)
          - 1911-1914(M-2796)
          - 1923-1926(M-2797)
          - 1926-1930(M-2798)
        - Union Church, Hillsboro District, Church Conference Minutes, 1883-1904(M-2789) (Box NCC35)
      - Milton Circuit/Charge, Durham District, 1894-1901, 1902-1908
        - Quarterly Conference Minutes
          - 1894-1897(M-2805)
          - 1898-1901(M-2806)
          - 1902-1908(M-2814)
            Includes Person Co., Woodsdale Circuit/Charge.
      - Yanceyville Circuit, multiple districts, 1855-1877, 1891-1902
        1844-1858: Circuit in Danville District
        1858-1872: Circuit in Greensboro District
        1872-1877: Circuit in Hillsboro District
        1891-1902: Circuit in Durham District
        - Quarterly Conference Minutes
          - 1844-1877
            Includes Caswell Circuit, 1844-1854.
          - 1891-1894(M-2815)
          - 1895-1899(M-2816)
          - 1899-1902(M-2817)
    - Chatham Co., 1833-1841, 1854-1943
      [For more on Chatham Co., see also the Historical Sketches Series, Ministers Subseries, Asbury, Francis.]
      - [Chatham Circuit, multiple districts, 1833-1841: Found in Randolph Co., Franklinsville Circuit, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1849-1871.] (Box NCC36)
      - Pittsboro Circuit/Church/Charge, multiple districts, 1854-1943
        1854-1887: Circuit in Fayetteville District
        1888-1894: Circuit in Durham District
        1895-1927: Circuit in Fayetteville District
        1926/1927-1930: Circuit in Durham District
        1930-1934: Circuit in Fayetteville District
        1939-1943: Circuit in Durham District
        - Church Register, 1894-1901(F-2807)
        - Quarterly Conference Minutes/Records
          - 1854-1923, (2 folders)
          - [1868-1887: Found in Alamance Co., Haw River Circuit, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1854-1887.]
          - 1888-1891(M-2808)
          - 1892-1894(M-2809)
          - 1895-1898(M-2865)
          - 1899-1902(M-2866)
          - 1903-1906(M-2867)
          - 1907-1910(M-2868)
          - 1911-1914(M-2869) (Box NCC37)
          - 1915-1918(M-2870)
          - 1919-1922(M-2871)
          - 1923-1927(M-2872)
          - 1926-1930(M-2810)
          - 1930-1934(M-2873)
          - 1939-1943(M-2812)
    - Chowan Co., 1896-1897
      - Chowan Circuit, Elizabeth City District, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1896-1897 (M-2823) (Box NCC37)
      - [Gates and Edenton Circuit, multiple districts, 1822-1824: Found in Gates Co., Gates Circuit, Recording Steward's Book, 1817-1872.]
    - Cleveland Co., 1868-1895 (See also the Western N.C. conference.)
      - Double Shoals Circuit, Shelby District, Quarterly Conference Records, 1884-1887 (M-2887) (Box NCC37)
      - Rock Spring Circuit, Shelby District, 1868-1895 (Box NCC38)
        - Church Register, 1881-1895(M-2889)
        - Quarterly Conference Minutes
          - [1868-1876: Found in Lincoln Co., Lincolnton Circuit, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1828-1876.]
          - [1877-1880(F-2890): Removed to Oversize Materials, Box OS3.]
    - [Craven Co.: See Carteret and Craven Cos.]
    - Currituck Co., 1829-1860, 1867-1870, 1907-1910 (Box NCC38)
      - Currituck Circuit, Norfolk District, 1829-1860
        At least 1859: Circuit in Norfolk District, Va. Conference
        - Mount Zion Meeting House, (MEC), Church Book, 1829-1838
          Includes records of an abstinence society and an annotated members list.
        - Letter from J. B. Houk, 1860
          Includes description and plan of circuit.
        - [Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1859: Found in Dare Co., Dare Circuit, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1859-1878.]
      - [Currituck Mission, multiple districts, 1860, 1867-1870: Found in Dare Co., Dare Circuit, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1859-1878.]
      - Moyock Circuit, Elizabeth City District, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1907-1910 (M-2846)
    - Dare Co., 1859-1878, 1887-1913
      - Dare Circuit, multiple districts, 1859-1878, 1889-1903 (Box NCC38)
        At least 1860: Circuit in Norfolk District, Va. Conference
        At least 1871: Circuit in Murfreesboro District, Va. Conference
        At least 1872: Circuit in Norfolk District, Va. Conference
        Probably 1872-1890: Circuit in Murfreesboro District, Va. Conference
        1889-1895: Circuit in Washington District, N.C. Conference
        1896-1903: Circuit in Elizabeth City District, N.C. Conference
        - Quarterly Conference Minutes
          - 1859-1878(M-2934)
            Includes Currituck Circuit, 1859; Currituck Mission, 1860 and 1867-1870; and Dare Mission, 1871-1872.
          - 1888-1891(M-2949)
            Includes Roanoke Island and Dare Circuit, 1888. Also available on microfilm.
          - 1892-1895(M-2897)
          - 1896-1899(M-2826)
          - 1900-1903(M-2827)
      - [Dare Mission, multiple districts, 1859-1872: Found in Dare Co., Dare Circuit, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1859-1878.]
      - Hatteras Circuit, multiple districts, 1887-1890, 1896-1911
        1887-1890: Circuit in Washington District
        1896-1911: Circuit in Elizabeth City District
        - Quarterly Conference Minutes
          - 1887-1890(M-2899)
          - 1896-1899(M-2832)
          - 1900-1903(M-2833) (Box NCC39)
          - 1904-1907(M-2834)
          - 1908-1911(M-2835)
      - Kitty Hawk Charge, Elizabeth City District, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1910
      - Kitty Hawk Circuit, Elizabeth City District, 1896-1899, 1904-1911
        - Quarterly Conference Minutes
          - 1896-1899(M-2843)
          - 1904-1907(M-2844)
          - 1908-1911(M-2845)
      - Kitty Hawk Mission, multiple districts, 1888-1891
        1888-1890: Mission in Murfreesboro District, Va. Conference
        Beginning 1891: Mission in Washington District, N.C. Conference
        - Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1888-1891(M-2940)
      - Roanoke Island Circuit/Station, multiple districts, 1888, 1892-1913
        Until 1890: Circuit in Murfreesboro District, Va. Conference
        1892-1895: Circuit in Washington District, N.C. Conference
        1896-1913: Circuit in Elizabeth City District, N.C. Conference
        - Quarterly Conference Minutes
          - [1888: Found in Dare Co., Dare Circuit, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1888-1891.]
          - 1892-1895(M-2900)
          - 1896-1899(M-2858)
          - 1900-1903(M-2859) (Box NCC40)
          - 1904-1907(M-2860)
          - 1908-1911(M-2861)
          - 1900-1913
    - [Dare and Pamlico Cos.: See Pamlico and Dare Cos.]
    - Durham Co., 1885-1941, 1944-1956, 1961-1963, 1966, 1969-1970
      - Carr Church, Durham District, Register of Members, 1887-1897 (M-2767) (Box NCC40)
      - Duke Memorial Church, Durham District, 1885-1941, 1944-1956, 1961-1963, 1966, 1969-1970 (See also Main Street Church/Charge.)
        - Board of Stewards' Minutes
          - 1916-1923(M-2768)
          - 1945 Jan.-1956 June, (1-3 of 5 folders)
          - 1945 Jan.-1956 June, (4-5 of 5 folders) (Box NCC41)
        - Church Directories, 1966, 1969
        - Church Register, 1885-1924(F-2780)
        - Commemorative Programs, 1944, 1963
        - Epworth League
          - Annual Report, 1909(M-2769)
          - Record Book, 1911(M-2770)
          - Record Book, Senior Division, 1911-1912(M-2771)
        - Historical Materials, 1886-1932, 1954, 1966, 1970
        - List of Members
          - 1919-1923(M-2772)
          - 1924(M-2773)
        - Pastor's Aides Bulletin, 1961-1962
        - Quarterly Conference Minutes/Records
          - 1915-1920(M-2774)
          - 1921-1924(M-2775) (Box NCC42)
          - 1925-1928(M-2776)
          - 1928-1932(M-2777)
          - 1933-1935(M-2778)
          - 1935-1941(L-2779)
        - Women's Missionary Society
          - Minutes and papers, 1919-1933
          - Minutes
            - 1917 Sept.-1922 Oct. 9 (M-2781)
            - 1922 Nov.-1925 July (M-2782) (Box NCC43)
            - 1934-1935(M-2783)
          - Roll Book
            - 1912-1924(M-2784)
            - 1927-1929
      - Durham Circuit, Durham District, 1889-1934
        - Church Register
          - 1889-1906(M-2786)
          - 1908-1925(F-2787)
        - Quarterly Conference Minutes
          - 1895-1898(M-2757)
          - 1903-1906(M-2758)
          - 1907-1910(M-2759)
          - 1911-1914(M-2760)
          - 1915-1918(M-2761) (Box NCC44)
          - 1919-1922(M-2762)
          - 1922-1926(M-2763)
          - 1927-1930(M-2764)
          - 1930-1934(M-2765)
      - [Front Street Church, Durham District, 1900: Found in Alamance Co., Burlington Charge, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1897-1900.]
      - Gregson Street Church, Durham District, Register of Members, 1908-1927 (F-2788)
      - Main Street Church/Charge, Durham District, 1885-1910 (See also Durham Co., Duke Memorial Church.)
        - Bethany Sunday School, 1891-1896, (2 folders)
        - Board of Stewards' Record of Proceedings, 1891-1908(M-2800)
        - Church Assessments, 1900(L-2801) (Box NCC45)
        - Quarterly Conference Minutes/Records
          - 1890-1893(M-2751)
          - 1894-1898(M-2752)
          - 1899-1902(M-2754)
          - 1903-1906(M-2755)
          - 1906-1910(M-2802)
        - Register of Members
          - 1885-1909(F-2803)
          - 1890(M-2804)
    - Forsyth Co., 1857-1866, 1875-1876
      - Forsyth Circuit, multiple districts, 1857-1866, 1875-1876 (Box NCC46)
        1857-1858: Circuit in Salisbury District
        1858-1867: Circuit in Greensboro District
        - Mt. Pleasant Church, Class Book, 1857-1866
        - Plan of Forsyth Circuit and Preacher's Class Book, 1875-1876
    - Gaston Co., 1864-1890
      - Gaston Circuit, Shelby District, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1864-1890 (Box NCC46)
        Includes Lincolnton Station, 1864-1868; Lincolnton Circuit, 1869-1881; and Stanley Creek Circuit, 1890.
      - [Stanley Creek Circuit, Shelby District, 1890: Found in Gaston Co., Gaston Circuit, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1864-1890.]
    - Gates Co., 1784-1937
      [For more on Gates Co., see also the Historical Sketches Series, Ministers Subseries, Asbury, Francis.]
      - [Bertie Circuit, multiple districts, 1817-1822: Found in Gates Co., Gates Circuit, Recording Steward's Book, 1817-1872.] (Box NCC46)
      - Gates Circuit, multiple districts, 1784-1911
        1784-1817: Circuit in Suffolk and other districts, Va. Conference
        1817-1855: Circuit in Norfolk District, Va. Conference
        1855-1856: Circuit in Murfreesboro District, Va. Conference
        1856-1858: Circuit in Norfolk and Murfreesboro District, Va. Conference
        1858-1866: Circuit in Norfolk District, Va. Conference
        1866-1877?: Circuit in Suffolk and other districts, Va. Conference
        1872?-1891: Circuit in Murfreesboro District, Va. Conference
        Until 1895: Circuit in Va. Conference
        After 1895: Circuit in Elizabeth City District, N.C. Conference
        - [Church Register, Suffolk and Other Districts, 1784-1840, 1866-1877 (F-5016): Removed to Oversize Materials, Box OS4. Also available on microfilm.]
        - Quarterly Conference Minutes
          - 1872-1891(F-2936)
          - 1891-1895(M-2937)
          - 1896-1899(M-2928)
          - 1900-1903(M-2929)
          - 1904-1907(M-2830)
          - 1908-1911(M-2831)
        - Recording Steward's Book and laid in records (financial reports to Quarterly Conference), 1817-1872, (2 folders) (Box NCC47)
          Includes Bertie Circuit, 1817-1822; Gates and Bertie Circuit, 1830-1831; Gates and Edenton Circuit, 1822-1824; Gates Circuit, 1825-1872; and Murfreesboro and Gates Circuit, 1824-1825.
      - [Gates and Bertie Circuit, multiple districts, 1830-1831: Found in Gates Co., Gates Circuit, Recording Steward's Book, 1817-1872.]
      - North Gates Charge, Suffolk District, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1892-1894 (Box NCC48)
      - North Gates Circuit, multiple districts, 1884-1937
        1888-1890: Circuit in Murfreesboro District, Va. Conference
        1891-1892: Circuit in Suffolk District, Va. Conference
        Until 1985: Circuit in Va. Conference
        - [Church Register 1884-1937 (F-5013): Removed to Oversize Materials, Box OS5.]
        - Quarterly Conference Minutes
          - 1888-1892(M-2941)
          - 1892-1895 (M-2942 and one folder)
          - 1895-1898(M-2848)
          - 1898-1902(M-2849)
          - 1907-1910(M-2943)
    - Guilford Co., 1832-1883
      - Guilford Circuit, Greensboro District, 1832-1865 (Box NCC48)
        - Quarterly Conference Minutes
          - 1832-1865 (L-3543 and one folder) (Also available on microfilm.)
            Missing 1854-1861. Includes Xerox copies of pages 1-37.
          - [1861: Found in Guilford Co., South Guilford and Pleasant Garden Circuits, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1861-1883.]
      - [Guilford Mission, Hillsboro District, 1867: Found in Randolph Co., Franklinsville Circuit, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1849-1871.]
      - [Pleasant Garden Circuit, Greensboro District, 1880-1883: Found in Guilford Co., South Guilford and Pleasant Garden Circuits, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1861-1883.]
      - South Guilford Circuit, Greensboro District, 1862-1879
        - Quarterly Conference Minutes
          - [1862: Found in Randolph Co., Franklinsville Circuit, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1849-1871.]
          - [1863-1879: Found in Guilford Co., South Guilford and Pleasant Garden Circuits, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1861-1883.]
      - South Guilford and Pleasant Garden Circuits, multiple districts, 1861-1883
        1863-1865: Circuit in Trinity College District
        1867-1872: Circuit in Hillsboro District
        1880: Pleasant Garden Circuit established
        - Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1861-1883
          Includes Guilford Circuit, 1861; Franklinsville Circuit, 1862; South Guilford Circuit, 1863-1879; Trinity College Circuit, 1863; Pleasant Garden Circuit, 1880-1883. There are no minutes for 1866-1867 and 1873.
    - Halifax Co., 1882-1885 and undated
      - Roanoke Circuit, Warrenton District, 1882-1885 and undated (Box NCC48)
        Circuit located mostly in Halifax Co., N.C., but also includes town of Littleton, Warren Co. Includes Tabor Church, Calvary Church, New Hope Church, Littleton Church, Bethel Church, and Pegram's Church, as well as an inventory of parsonage furniture (1882). Edward Alston Thorne was a prominent layman.
        - Quarterly Conference Financial Papers, 1885 and undated
        - Quarterly Conference Record Book, 1882-1885
    - Hertford Co., 1824-1825
      - [Murfreesboro and Gates Circuit, multiple districts, 1824-1825: Found in Gates Co., Gates Circuit, Recording Steward's Book, 1817-1872.] (Box NCC48)
    - Iredell Co., 1823-1873
      - Friendship Congregation (MP), unknown district, meeting minutes, 1871 (Box NCC49)
      - Iredell Circuit, multiple districts, 1823-1873
        1823-1835: Circuit in Yadkin District, Va. Conference
        1835-1838: Circuit in Salisbury District, Va. Conference
        1838-1873: Circuit in Salisbury District, N.C. Conference
        - Church Records, 1834-1850(L-2885)
          Volume includes notes and drawings on church buildings. Also includes a photographic copy of one of the church building drawings.
        - Quarterly Conference Minutes
          - 1823-1851(M-2939)
          - 1852-1873(M-2886)
    - Lincoln Co., 1828-1881 (See also the Western N.C. Conference.)
      - Lincolnton Circuit, multiple districts, 1828-1867, 1869-1881 (Box NCC49)
        1828-1852: Circuit in Lincolnton District, S.C. Conference
        1853-1854: Circuit in Spartanburg District, S.C. Conference
        1855-1859: Circuit in Shelby District, S.C. Conference
        1860-1862: Circuit in Lincolton District, S.C. Conference
        1863: Circuit in Catawba District, S.C. Conference
        1864-1869: Circuit in Shelby District, S.C. Conference
        1870-1876: Circuit in Shelby District, N.C. Conference
        - Quarterly Conference Minutes
          - 1828-1876
            Includes Rock Spring Circuit, 1868-1876.
          - [1869-1881: Found in Gaston Co., Gaston Circuit, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1864-1890.] (Box NCC50)
      - [Lincolnton Station, Shelby District, 1864-1868: Found in Gaston Co., Gaston Circuit, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1864-1890.]
    - Montgomery Co., 1854-1880
      - Montgomery Circuit, multiple districts, 1854-1880 (Box NCC50)
        Until 1858: Circuit in Fayetteville District
        After 1858: Circuit in Greensboro District
        - Mt. Olivet Church, Class book, 1854-1880(S-2722)
    - New Hanover Co., 1844-1905
      - Fifth Street Charge/Church/Station, Wilmington District, 1844-1905 (Box NCC50)
        - Church Conference Minutes, 1903-1905(M-2912)
        - Church Register
          - 1851-1884(M-2925)
          - 1885-1888(M-2921)
        - Quarterly Conference Minutes/Records
          - 1844-1870(M-2919)
          - 1873-1880(M-2920)
          - 1880-1888(M-2909)
          - 1888-1892(M-2910) (Box NCC51)
          - 1892-1896(M-2922)
          - 1896-1900(M-2911)
          - 1900-1904(M-2923)
          - 1904-1905
    - Pamlico and Dare Cos., 1892-1895
      - Ocracoke and Hatteras Circuit, Washington District, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1892-1895 (M-2720) (Box NCC51)
    - Pasquotank Co., 1852-1887, 1892-1906
      - Elizabeth City Station, probably Elizabeth City District, 1858-1873 (Box NCC51)
        [For more on Elizabeth City Station, see also Historical Sketches Series, Ministers Subseries, Overman, John P.]
        - A Record of the Proceedings of the Board of Official Members, 1858-1873
      - Kitrell's Church, Elizabeth City District, 1898-1904
        - Church Conference Minutes, 1898-1904(M-2842)
        - Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1899
      - Pasquotank Circuit, multiple districts, 1852-1887, 1892-1899, 1902-1906
        1854-1855: Circuit in Norfolk District, Va. Conference
        1858: Circuit in Norfolk District, Va. Conference
        1883-1887: Circuit in Murfreesboro District, Va. Conference
        1892-1894: Circuit in Suffolk District, Va. Conference
        1895: Circuit in Elizabeth City District, N.C. Conference.
        Circuit located in Pasquotank, Perquimans, and Camden counties and includes McBrides Church, Newland Church, Newbegun Church, Union Church, Mt. Hermon Church, Halls Creek Church, Oak Grove Church, New Hope Church, Concord Church, Providence Church, Mt. Zion Church, and Woodville Church.
        - Church Register, 1854-1858(M-2944)
        - Quarterly Conference Minute Book/Minutes (Box NCC52)
          - 1852-1883
          - 1883-1887(M-2945)
          - 1892-1899 (four folders)
          - 1902-1906, (2 folders)
    - Perquimans Co., 1874-1918
      - Hertford Church, Elizabeth City District, Sunday School Record Book, 1904-1905 (M-2841) (Box NCC52)
      - Hertford Circuit, multiple districts, 1874-1904
        1874-1891: Circuit in Murfreesboro District, Va. Conference
        1895-1904: Circuit in Elizabeth City District, N.C. Conference
        - Quarterly Conference Minutes
          - 1874-1891(F-2836)
          - 1892-1894(M-2938) (Box NCC53)
          - 1894-1897(M-2837)
          - 1898(M-2838)
          - 1899-1902(M-2839)
          - 1902-1904(M-2840)
      - [Pasquotank Circuit, multiple districts: See Pasquotank Co., Pasquotank Circuit.]
      - Perquimans Circuit, multiple districts, 1892-1918
        Until 1895: Circuit in Suffolk District, Va. Conference
        - Quarterly Conference Minutes
          - 1892-1895 (four folders)
          - 1895-1898(M-2852)
          - 1898-1902(M-2853)
          - 1902-1906(M-2854) (Box NCC54)
          - 1906-1910(M-2855)
          - 1910-1914(M-2856)
          - 1914-1918(M-2857)
    - Person Co., 1902-1903
      - [Woodsdale Circuit/Charge, Durham District, 1902-1903: Found in Caswell Co., Milton Circuit, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1902-1908.] (Box NCC54)
    - Randolph Co., 1841-1872, 1875-1899 (See also the Western N.C. Conference.)
      - [Franklinsville and Cedar Falls Station, various districts, 1872: Found in Randolph Co., Franklinsville Circuit, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1849-1872.] (Box NCC54)
      - Franklinsville Circuit, multiple districts, 1849-1872
        1833-1838: Circuit in Danville District, Va. Conference
        1838-1841: Circuit in Greensboro District, N.C. Conference
        1849-1850: Circuit in Raleigh District, N.C. Conference
        1850-1862: Circuit in Greensboro District, N.C. Conference
        1862-1865: Circuit in Trinity College District, N.C. Conference
        1865-1872: Circuit in Hillsboro District, N.C. Conference
        - Quarterly Conference Minutes
          - 1849-1872(F-2880)
            Includes Chatham Circuit, 1833-1841; Guilford Mission, 1867; South Guilford Circuit, 1862; and Franklinsville and Cedar Falls Station, 1872.
          - [1862: Found in Guilford Co., South Guilford and Pleasant Garden Circuits, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1861-1883.]
      - Randolph Circuit, multiple districts, 1841-1854, 1875-1899
        1841-1854: Circuit in Greensboro District
        1875-1885: Circuit in Greensboro District
        1885-1898?: Circuit in Trinity College District
        1899?: Circuit in Greensboro District
        - Church Register (facsimile copy), 1885-1898
        - Quarterly Conference Minutes
          - 1875-1887
          - 1881-1899 and undated
            Includes ministers' reports.
          - 1888-1892(fascimile copy) (M-2891) (Box NCC55)
            Contains lists of members and registers of deaths and disposals, baptisms, and marriages. Purchased and begun by Rev. Frank H. Wood. Includes Trinity College Church. Original register is in the custody of the Mt. Vernon United Methodist Church, Trinity, N.C.
        - Tabernacle and Union Churches, 1841-1854
          - Sunday School Minute Book 1841-1854(M-3830)
      - [Trinity College Circuit, multiple districts, 1863: Found in Guilford Co., South Guilford and Pleasant Garden Circuits, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1861-1883.]
    - Richmond Co., 1845-1869
      - Rockingham Circuit, Fayetteville District, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1845-1869 (Box NCC55)
    - Stokes Co., 1860-1877
      - Stokes Circuit, Greensboro District, 1860-1877 (Box NCC55)
        - Stokesburg Church, Class Book, 1860-1877
    - Tyrrel Co., 1892-1894, 1900-1903, 1908-1911
      - Columbia Circuit, Elizabeth City and Washington Districts, 1892-1894, 1900-1903, 1908-1911 (Box NCC55)
        1892-1894: Circuit in Washington District
        1900-1911: Circuit in Elizabeth City District
        - Quarterly Conference Minutes
          - 1892-1895(M-2896)
          - 1900-1903(M-2824)
          - 1908-1911(M-2825)
    - Union Co., 1877-1886
      - Monroe, Matthews and Clear Creek Circuits, Charlotte District (Box NCC55)
        - Register (Fascimile), 1877-1886
          [Patrons should use copies of register and then consult originals if required.]
        - Register (Original), 1877-1886 (Box NCC55A)
    - Wake Co., 1850-1853, 1855-1944 and undated
      - Buckhorn Circuit, multiple districts, 1850-1853, 1855-1901, and undated (Box NCC55)
        1869-1876?: Circuit in Raleigh District